<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[d-flipflop blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[A general blog on interesting, underdog projects with high potential in computer science..]]></description><link>https://dflipflop.com</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 09:59:10 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Coronavirus & the world's system.]]></title><description><![CDATA[I wrote this post sometime back on Facebook when the world was just getting ready to fight the Coronavirus, since then similar thoughts were…]]></description><link>https://dflipflop.com/hello-world/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://dflipflop.com/hello-world/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wrote this post sometime back on Facebook when the world was just getting ready to fight the Coronavirus, since then similar thoughts were expressed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://a16z.com/2020/04/18/its-time-to-build/&quot;&gt;Marc Andreessen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe corona virus isn’t that bad, maybe it doesn’t have the maximum mortality rate, maybe a lot of us will move past this untouched or recover just fine but what won’t leave us is the thing that how underprepared we are as a society, as a nation, as a world, as the only known supreme intelligence that exists in the universe. We’ve built all these systems over all these years, taxes, healthcare, hospitals, governments, sports, research etc. all these things but they’re fragile, they’re not resilient to a domino effect that collapses everything about how we operate this world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As conscious beings we take pride in how far we’ve come as a society, all the mechanisms that we’ve built, all the technologies that we’ve developed but it is not a system that is resilient to attacks as we’d like to think, it is not a system that can contain the impact, it is not a system where if a part of it fails, others run just fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It causes a domino effect, because people are sick or taking precautions, they won’t be able to produce, the supplies are affected and the demands rise, a positive feedback loop with respect to demand-supply ratio, it affects all walks of life and it has the potential to bring the world to its knees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world that we live in and all the systems that put together build the world are not fault tolerant, they are tightly coupled, it literally is a house of cards. Our fight for consciousness is a tough one and corona virus is maybe just the level x of y before we meet the final boss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything can go against us, corona virus could have been 100x more deadly. Climate change, the water scarcity, the population vs natural resources burden, these are anticipated challenges, we know they are coming, we are a little woke about them, we’re trying to make people aware about them but what about the challenges that we have not anticipated, something that never had our eyeballs, how ready are our systems for those.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We never designed the systems that we presently have, all of these were designed and implemented with far less knowledge about the world, with far less experience and with far less technological advancements. It would have been just fine if our systems would have evolved right, if we were iterating our systems but unfortunately we are not, we are now a multiple huge giant societies that are slow and only react when the doom is knocking at our door.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can’t argue if it’s the Capitalism vs Socialism debate that could have solved this, if it was any one form of societal structure that could have ended us in a win-win situation, maybe these structures are too old and rusted, as I said earlier, they were never created with the foreseeable future in mind but everyone just went along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We as a society, a country, as a world are the ones who determine the value of the consciousness that we yield, It is our systems that determine how much of impact on consciousness raises all the red-alarms in our systems. The more our systems value consciousness more are the chances of us winning the fight for the light of consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never started writing this before I had the key points for a lot more robust design for the systems in my mind, a design that is only evolving, a design that puts maximum value to the human consciousness, a design that is fault tolerant, the one which is able to contain and respond to both anticipated and unanticipated challenges. a design that is built for the foreseeable future, a design that leverages the best that the technology has to offer, a design where AI/advanced technologies would only facilitate the design.
a design where everyone works not to keep the system running but to advance the system, much like the developers of the system, In my opinion that would be a much better use of the human consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it too late to build such a system, maybe.
Are we too big a society for such a system to function, most likely.
Would such a design of systems better our chances of survival in the long run, definitely.
Am I just being existential amid what all’s going on around the world, we’ll have to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All these patches of my thoughts over the last few days don’t matter, a proposal for a redefined utopian society is maybe as good as electoral promises but maybe it is the right time to bring to the table the idea of flaws in our systems at the level of existence, the flaws that we have nonchalantly gotten used to because honestly this is the only world we have seen and we really don’t have previous standards to benchmark against.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>